According to reports from our allies,
an enemy cavalry of 300 burst
through the flame wall.
They're probably Kioka's elite forces,
equipped with air rifles.
We can bring 120 or so to engage them.
Considering our exhaustion
from the long battle...
The difference in force
is five to one, or so?
I see, I see.
How did it come to this, again?
You know exactly how.
It was your failure as commander
to fully understand the situation.
In other words...
I have to do something.
Second Lieutenant Matthew,
As of now, I'm putting you
in charge of this location.
Continue the mobile defense mission.
I'll leave all our air gunners.
Once we defend this place for
two more days, we can retreat.
Thanks.
Second Lieutenant Haroma.
Y-Yes?
Leave your second-in-command in charge
of the field hospital and rally the troops.
I'm not staying, Ikta.
Nana?
You promised to give us a place
where we all could live.
If you die, who'll do that?
Let me protect you, too!
All right.
Help me out!
Okay, then—
W-Wait, Ikta!
Two more days?
Do you think I can keep this
place safe for two days?
Oh, that.
To be honest, probably not.
But, you know, Matthew,
there's one order I'll never give
no matter how bad things get.
"Defend this to the death."
"Protect it with your lives."
It's too unscientific.
I'll make the order of things clear.
You protect this place safely.
That's the best outcome.
You're safe, but you
couldn't protect this place.
That's the next best.
The other two are equally bad.
Got it?
If you aren't safe,
the outcomes are all equally bad.
So, I'll just give you one order:
Live, Matthew,
and I'll see you in three days.
Damn it all.
Fine, I'll do it!
Okay, Yatori.
Ready to go have some fun with me?
Yes.
In A Twilight Empire
First Lieutenant, what's the plan?
I took a look.
Just as the map said,
there's a thin path along
the top of the rock wall.
I thought about sealing it, but...
If we can't restore the wall of fire beyond,
the enemy main unit will still
come storming through there.
Correct.
Just delaying them isn't good enough.
We need to defeat the enemy
and rebuild the fire wall.
The problem is the cavalry and air rifles.
If I can't do something about their
overwhelming offensive power...
Yatori, give me information.
Anything you've got.
I want to shake things up in my head.
There's a work area up ahead that
we were using to restore the fire wall.
There's still straw and logs there.
We can try to make a bad path
that horses won't want to travel.
He builds up information
and uses highly-trained troops to control
the entire battlefield to his liking.
That's the enemy commander's method.
That won't be enough to shake him up.
This... might work...
Would it work?
Jean, if they're going to counterattack,
it will be up here.
Yah!
It's the path we saw in the blimp.
I wonder what the enemy's got waiting for us.
Crossbows?
It would be faster to charge in
and wipe them out, but...
Jean, I smell oil.
I noticed, too.
I see.
A fire attack.
They've laid down straw soaked with oil
and will launch fire arrows when we charge.
Not a bad idea,
but I won't play into their hands.
Advance to a distance of 150 meters
from the enemy at a slow gait!
Then, form ranks and prepare to fire!
Okay, fire!
No, wait!
The oil smell has lessened?
Th-The enemy's below us?
C-Calm down!
More! More!
Cause more chaos!
Ikta! You're too far ahead!
I can't protect you!
He's not listening to you!
Damn it!
What's going on?
We're reforming ranks!
Gather up!
That was fast!
Now—
They tricked us.
Or, no... Did I just make a mistake?
Because it was such a desperate measure?
Nyatt! This was no desperate measure!
They got close to nullify the advantages
of our horses and air rifles!
That was a highly advanced tactical maneuver!
But that's why I can't forgive the man
who came up with this plan!
The result of all their planning
was this chaos?!
What's that?
Red and white stripes?
Meaning they're willing to negotiate!
Willing to negotiate?
Not "we want to negotiate"?
We won't propose a negotiation.
In this situation, that would mean
a declaration of surrender.
But, if we say we're willing to talk,
that puts you in a corner.
It's a strong message
that we're willing to fight to the last man,
but if they give in, we'll listen.
Does this mean
they're waiting for us to break?
You can't handle this.
I know you can't handle this.
You're a greedy man who wants to put
the whole battlefield under his control.
What people like that hate the most
is when the battlefield
falls into complete chaos!
J-Jean?
What's wrong?
Give in already!
Move us to the next stage!
We're both sick of this battle!
Cease fighting!
First Lieutenant Yatorishino Igsem
with the Imperial Army.
May I speak with your commander?
Major in the Kioka Army, Jean Alkiniks.
I'm a guest officer with
the Holy Army of La Saia Alderamin.
I'm honored by the opportunity to meet
the Unsleeping, Shining Officer.
And I'm honored by the bad luck to
run into Igsem of the Sword here.
Let us negotiate, then.
A moment.
Our commander will handle that.
It's not you?
I'm sorry I'm late.
First Lieutenant Ikta Solork
of the Imperial Army.
I am the commander of this unit.
We seek a full surrender from you.
There's no way you can win
if you continue this battle,
and we don't want needless casualties.
I understand.
And I say that we completely refuse.
Can't say I approve of sending your soldiers
to pointless deaths, Lieutenant Solork.
You have only one path you should take,
and that's surrender.
In a battle of numbers,
we will win, for sure.
If you really think so,
we're wasting our time.
Why not restart the battle right now?
We'll give you our terms as well.
We'd like you to pull back to
the other side of the forest.
We will finish our retreat in two days.
It's true that I don't want any more battle,
but I cannot simply retreat.
I'm here to bring victory to
the Holy Army of Aldera.
If you're unwilling to agree to these terms,
we'll have to fight,
whether we like it or not.
If we do fight,
we will be the ones to survive.
A war of attrition is
the worst outcome for me as well,
but if it's my only choice,
I'll resign myself to it.
However, surely you're not
as willing to die as you might say?
You have one thing right,
and one thing wrong.
First, what you got right:
I'm not willing to die, no.
And the mistake:
It won't be you who survives.
Dyculous!
Enough bluffing.
I know exactly how much manpower you have.
You're looking at this the wrong way.
What?
You just said that you'll be
the ones to survive, yes?
That's not happening unless
you personally survive, is it?
Kus.
What's this?!
Don't move!
Or your commander will die.
Oh, dear.
You think a beam of light will kill me?
It looks nice and round,
like a shooting target, doesn't it?
You've heard of the Remeon family,
famed for their gunners, right?
I have one of them here.
Second Lieutenant Torway Remeon.
Of course, he's got an air rifle.
Don't think about getting off your horse.
That's the signal I gave him.
This is a violation of military treaty.
Attacks during negotiations aren't allowed.
If we're negotiating, yes.
But negotiations need to be
held willingly by two parties.
If you're not retreating,
I'll lower my negotiating flag
immediately and kill you.
We've only got the one flag up.
It won't take long to lower it.
We're ready to lower it immediately,
depending on what you do.
Nyatt!
This is no negotiation!
It's just a threat!
What's the difference between
negotiations and threats during wartime?
You're just calling the negotiations a threat
because they're not going your way.
And if I tell you I'm willing to die here?
That's not like you.
The right answer for you is
the one that doesn't cost you
or your men your lives for nothing.
You've only just met me.
Are you telling me you know me that well?
Just met you?
Don't be so cold.
For the past six days, it's felt like
I've been playing chess with you.
If you won't accept my terms,
I'll use force.
You and I both have that in common.
The one difference is that
I put my forces in a place where
I could aim directly at you,
and you failed to prepare for that.
He's lying!
I know that!
If he really had an air rifle unit,
he should bring some of them here to
make the threat seem more realistic.
There's a 90% chance it's a bluff.
But...
You can't ignore that 10% possibility!
We accept your conditions.
There's nothing to be ashamed of.
That was the right choice,
Major Jean Alkiniks.
I borrowed your ghost, Torway.
Okay, set the fire.
Lieutenant Solork!
There's something I want to ask.
I believe in the ideals of Kioka,
and I'm fighting to make them real.
What moves you to protect the Empire?
Unfortunately,
I've never wanted to protect my country.
What I've always wanted to protect,
and sometimes failed to protect, are people.
Nyatt!
It is the job of the nation
to protect those people!
And for that to happen,
heroes like you will be drained dry
and then tossed aside.
Since you don't even know it,
you're even more pitiable
than a slave right now.
Since you're working hard in the wrong way,
everyone else around you
is lazy in the wrong way.
Like a giant trying to hold the whole
world on a tray on his shoulders!
I'll give you some wise words,
Unsleeping, Shining Officer.
All heroes die of overwork.
Damn you, Ikta Solork!
I'll make the world into
the way it should be!
I promise!
Excuse me, Princess Chamille.
The troops are returning
from the Northern Garrison!
Solork!
Yatori!
Torway! Matthew!
Haro!
I'm right here!
If you hear me, then answer!
Yatori!
I'm sorry we're late.
We have returned, Princess Chamille.
Sorry for worrying you, Princess.
Torway, Matthew, Haro...
You're all so thin and pale.
Where's Solork?
Where is he?
Oh, right.
I'm right here, Princess.
Solork!
Solork! Solork!
I'm so glad... I'm so glad you're safe...
I almost wasn't just now.
S-Sorry.
And Princess,
it's not just us you should be trying
to encourage right now, is it?
I'm sorry.
I've shamed myself in front of
those that worked the hardest.
You really fought well.
The only reason the Empire can still count
the Northern Region among its territory
is because you stopped the Alderan invasion!
I'm grateful for your efforts,
and I feel sorrow for your losses.
I, Chamille Kitra Katjvanmaninik,
swear that I will reward you
for all you've done!
One Month Later
You oppressed the Sinack
for meaningless reasons,
needlessly cost soldiers their lives,
and your imprudence invited
an enemy invasion.
Because of your foolish actions,
the war to defend
the Northern Region continues.
Lieutenant General Tamtooktsk Safida,
you are hereby demoted to private,
stripped of your decorations,
and are ordered to be executed
as the highest class of war criminal.
N-No!
P-Please don't kill me!
A-Anything but that!
So what did you want, Princess?
Want to complain at me for something?
Solork,
what do you think about the present
state of the Katjvarna Empire?
Well, it's going downhill pretty fast.
Its influence is waning,
its politics get more corrupt by the day,
the Emperor is now just a puppet,
and he is failing to fulfill
his duties as ruler.
That was harsh.
However, I completely agree.
That is why I'd like to ask something of you.
Ikta Solork.
Rise to the top of the Imperial Army
and change this country from its core.
Don't tell me you can't do it.
You have military talent.
Overwhelming talent.
That's stupid.
Even if I do make it to the top,
what then?
You want me to start a coup?
I want you to lose a war.
And with that loss, save the country.
The loss will bring in
the Kioka Republic's culture,
economics, political philosophy...
Use all these external pressures
to purify the Empire.
But...
No, but then the Empire will
lose its unique culture—
I want you to lose the war
with enough power left to
stop that from happening.
That's what I want of you.
In other words, I...
You will lose the war in the right way.
You hate soldiers,
the imperial family, and heroes.
It's the perfect role for you.
So don't hesitate, Ikta Solork!
Come with me and fight until we lose!
You're late.
What did you talk about with the Princess?
Nothing.
Hey, Yatori.
Why do you think my dad died?
Because of some noble plot, maybe?
Because he was willing to disobey an
imperial order to protect the country?
Because he tried to keep your father
from falling from power?
It's all of those.
Basically, my dad died from overwork.
He tried to carry all the burdens himself
and died with no regard for
how the people around him felt.
Save the country by losing a war?
Princess, if I follow your plan,
it won't be too long before
I come into conflict
with this lady of Igsem,
guardians of the country.
If the country wants to die, let it.
It's all wrong.
What I want to save, what I want to protect,
has never been the country.
The one thing I won't allow is getting you
caught up in the collapse of the country.
That's why I came to take you, Yatori.
Please tell me you'll be
the one person not to forget that.
I could never forget, even if I wanted to.
The Invincible Lazy General.
The Heir to the Twin Blades.
And the Last Princess of the Empire.
The story that leads to the promised defeat
had only just begun.